JEFF D. MEAD

Software Development

Phone: 908-229-2034 LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/jeff-mead-58b6b8136/

Email: Jeffdmead171@gmail.com Twitter: twitter.com/JDM_Management

Accomplished Business Manager with over ten years of business operational experience. Pursuing a position in software development with a professional organization that will challenge and use my talents and experience to benefit both mutual growth and success.

Hard SkillsSoft SkillsLanguages & ProficiencyCoding, Debugging, Program AnalystBusiness Acumen, LeadershipJavaScript, CSS, HTML

Software Development Personnel Management COBOL, Visual Studio Code

Experience

Freelance Software Developer

2020

• Optimized and Debugged code across multiple applications to ensure the functionality of the code is working efficiently and correctly. Researching and Analyzing new concepts and programming languages for enhancing future projects.

Business Management/Operations Consultant

JDM Management Inc., NJ

2017 to 2020

• Owner and CEO of JDM Management, expert in combining financial, business and technology planning for organizational success. Focused to optimize long-term gains in performance, revenues and profitability for small businesses.

Director of Operations

The Kokes Organization Real Estate Firm, NJ

1995 to 2017

 Managed the daily business operations for a mid-size Real Estate Firm consisting of over 100 employee and over \$10 in annual revenue. Business activities included Sales, Budgeting, Forecasting, Financial Reporting, CRM Software, IT Support, Strategic Planning and Company Financial & Sales Presentations.

Computer Programmer/Analyst

Scudder, Stevens & Clark, New York City, NY

1989 to 1995

- Developed and Managed Programming Projects. Created CICS interface and maintained computer software for the reconciliation of financial transactions between brokerage house and bank institutions. Managed overnight batch processing for software and data updates to the financial system.
- Develop and coded computer software systems for brokerage client statement using COBOL & CICS. In charge of design, troubleshooting and month end runs of customer statements. On call 24/7 for technical support in case of system error and/or shut down.
- Developed & coded COBOL for financial systems and financial reporting. Projects included reconciliation of client dividend checks, batch runs for the maturity of fixed income investments and updated code in preparation of Y2K

Education

•	University of Central Florida, FL	Certificate, Coding Bootcamp: JAVA, JavaScript	2020
•	Monmouth University, NJ	MBA, Business Management & Administration	2011
•	Georgian Court University, NJ,	B.S., Business Management & Administration	1999
•	Brick Computer Science Institute, NJ	Certificate, COBOL, CICS, Mainframe	1990